# Theodora Nneoma Orji

Software Programmer +447424346916, theodoranneoma@gmail.com, Newcastle, UK linkedin.com/theodora-orji

#### **PROFILE**

As a software programmer with strong front-end programming skills, I am proficient in developing web experiences that put an emphasis on both functionality and aesthetics. I am proficient in Javascript and Typescript and libraries like ReactJs and React Native. I firmly believe in the importance of cross-browser compatibility, performance optimisation, and UI design principles. I'm deepening my grasp of backend frameworks, such as SQL and PHP. I have a collaborative attitude and am dedicated to keeping up with industry trends, so I'm always ready to contribute my expertise and creativity to your team's efforts to create exceptional digital experiences. I equally volunteer during my free time to teach kids and young people about pursuing a career in Tech.

# **SKILLS**

- React JS
- React Native
- Oracle SQL
- NextJs
- Javascript
- HTML/CSS

- PHP
- Typescript
- Tailwind
- Expo
- Communication skills

# **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

AI Training Coding Expert (Contracted Freelancer)

Outlier

November 2024 - Till date

- Code Refinement and Enhancement: Focused on analyzing and updating existing code to meet evolving standards, improve efficiency, and support the creation of training sets used in machine learning models. Ensured that updated and refined code met high-quality standards necessary for training robust, efficient AI systems.
- Collaborative Problem-Solving: Partnered with cross-functional teams to address coding challenges, align project requirements, and contribute to a collaborative code improvement process.
- Documentation and Knowledge Sharing: Created and maintained detailed documentation on code changes, methodologies, and practices to streamline future development and training processes

# Frontend Developer

CallPhone LTD, Fintech Company, Abuja, Nigeria

February 2023 - February 2024

- Collaborated on code reviews with the product team, acquired insight from senior developers, and improved in writing scalable and custom code.
- Aided in designing and building dashboards to enhance 80% of users' experience on company products

• Ensured that all technical issues were ticketed, response to Tier 1 tickets, and escalation of issues at Tier 2

# Frontend programmer (Intern)

TIIDELAB, Abuja, Nigeria

June 2022 - Dec 2022

- Worked on a software requirement and Functional requirement document which enabled my team of 10 developers to implement and build the website feature of a whistleblowing platform.
- Conducted user research, which assisted in identifying components which will be implemented in the application.
- Participated in the user interface design process of the aforementioned website with the design team.
- Developed a working web based platform using ReactJs, CSS And NodeJs Framework.

# EDUCATION

**MSc**, Computer Science

Northumbria University, Newcastle.

Relevant Courses: Object Oriented programming, Java, PHP, SQL and Database Management systems.

## BSc, Education

University Of Port Harcourt, Nigeria.

Sept 2015 - Nov 2019

Second Class Honors (Upper division) in Humana Kinetics and Health Education

## COURSES AND CERTIFICATION

- Information Technology Essentials (Udemy) | 2021
- Introduction to AI, Machine Learning and Python basics (Udemy) | 2021
- Data Analytics (Side Hustle) | 2021
- Frontend Development (TIIDELAB) | 2022

#### REFEREES

Available on Request